# Scott Shepherd

**UX Designer and Product Owner** 

scott@scotts.design 206-356-4695

www.linkedin.com/in/scott-shepherd/

#### Introduction

I have been an Owner/Partner at Solid State Pros LLC, a digital agency, for 3 years. We use an Agile philosophy to accomplish everything from small business needs to tier 1 company software solutions. My life pursuit is in understanding experience. I am mainly interested in projects and products that incorporate investigation in the motivations and passion behind users and customers.

**Roles** I've performed in the product lifecycle:

UX Designer

- Creative Director
- Project Manager

- Graphic Designer
- Product Owner
- Video Producer

**3** tactics I use to increase project success and team collaboration:

- 1. **The Amazon Backwards Press Release**: Define your vision and goal, then build the steps needed to achieve it.
- 2. Create **User Stories**: Ground the project in real life and emotional frameworks.
- 3. **Agile (Scrum)** methodology for iterative project development.

Portfolio: www.scotts.design, created using Bootstrap, HTML5, and CSS3.

## Technologies I use

- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe InDesign
- Adobe Premiere
- Adobe After Effects

- Adobe Experience
  Design
- Invision
- Sketch
- Zeplin
- HTML5

- CSS3
- Bootstrap
- Github
- Microsoft Office
- JIRA
- Slack

# **Recent Experience**

UX Designer at Filter Digital www.filterdigital.com

2017

This project entails working closely with a UX Researcher and a Marketing Manager in order to create prototypes.

Creative Director, UX Designer, Graphic Designer, and Owner/Manager at Solid State Pros LLC www.solidstatepros.com

2014 - 2017

Notable Projects:

**Stoel Rives LLP:** proprietary software for a tier 1 company used to ticket and escalate incidents in a privacy suite

My roles: UX Designer, Product Owner, and Client Manager

- Lead a design team towards a simple and clear user interface
- Worked directly with the client to create user stories and timelines
- Used Adobe Illustrator and Photoshop to create mockups for review and design for developers
- Daily scrum meetings with developers to guide implementation of features

**Hyla Mobile: TrueTap:** <a href="www.truetap.mobi">www.truetap.mobi</a> mobile app designed to facilitate the assessment and value of a mobile device and direct them towards nearby resellers

My roles: User Researcher, UX Designer, Brand Team, and QA tester

- Used Adobe Illustrator and Photoshop to create concepts and mockups for branding and UX direction
- Conducted **face to face interviews** with potential customers
- Created user personas and infographics
- Held creative meetings to elicit ideas for direction and mood

**Skybridge LLC:** <u>www.skybridgesolution.com</u> Outsourcing manufacturing company rebranding to approach US tech market

My roles: Brand Lead, UX Designer, Graphic Designer, Developer, and Researcher

- **Led a branding team** to create concepts, moodboards, and mockups
- Used Adobe Illustrator to create logos for reviews, iterations, illustrations, and a final logo
- Performed **research** into user base, potential clients, and current competitors in order to create something original and impressionable.
- Using a **Bootstrap** template I used **HTML5** and **CSS3** to create the website

**Merry Go Ride:** Merry Go Ride Prototype Create a style guide, UI design, developer schemata, and clickable prototype for a ride service app for children

My roles: **UX Designer and Graphic Designer** 

 Using Adobe Experience Design I create a clickable prototype, style guide, UX design, and developer schemata in one easy location

**Law Offices of SaraEllen Hutchison, PLLC:** <a href="www.saraellenhutchison.com">www.saraellenhutchison.com</a> Create a marketing and blogging site for a Law Office

My Roles: **UX Design, Project Manager, Client Manager** 

- Collect requirements from client and formulate feature list
- Present **Drupal** choices and theming to client
- Mock up page layout and experience
- Coordinate with developer and deliver on time
- Continuing relationship with support and maintenance

**Lake City Hub**: <u>Lake City Hub Prototype</u> Create a UX design and clickable prototype for the Lake City Hub application

My roles: **UX Designer and Graphic Designer** 

• Using **Adobe Experience Design** I created a clickable prototype

**Epicmeet**: <u>www.epicmeetapp.com</u> Produce a commercial for Epicmeet, an app designed to bring boardgamers together that appeals to its key demographic using a limited budget for live action video. Epic Meet Video

My roles: **Producer, Director, Editor, and Screenwriter** 

- Developed timeline and budget for project
- Hired a Director of Photography, actors, makeup artist, and crew
- Facilitated the rental and logistics behind equipment
- Scouted locations
- Facilitated the scripting team
- Create shot list
- Chose music and sounds
- Edited footage with Adobe Premiere
- Facilitated hosting and linking with marketing website

**Vett.cloud**: Create a brand, logo, style guide, and 2 animated videos conveying value and explaining the product, which brings together stakeholders in a project and lets them analyze an opportunity anonymously

Roles: Brand Lead, Animator, and Sound Technician

- Used **Adobe Illustrator** to create mockups
- Using Adobe After Effects to create an animation highlighting the value proposition of the product: Vett.cloud Value
- Using Adobe Audition, Adobe Illustrator, and Videoscribe to create a white boarding animation that explains the product: <u>Vett.cloud Explanation</u>

#### Project Manager at Motive LLC <u>www.createmotive.com</u>

2017, As Project Manager I facilitated design and development for various client websites.

**Gelotte Hommas Drivdahl Website**: Facilitate the development of designed comps.

www.theartofarchitecture.com

My role: **Project Manager** 

- Using **Adobe Illustrator** adjust and export various assets as needed for development
- Using **JIRA** to track the production workflow

Creative Director, UX Designer, and Brand Strategist for NED Learning www.nedlearning.com

2016 - 2017, As Creative Director I facilitated branding, character design, graphics, and UX design on various projects. I am also an owner and help develop strategy.

 Using Adobe Illustrator I created a logo, brand assets, a learning board game, and worksheets

### **Education**

## Bachelor of Science in Cognitive Psychology

Evergreen State College 2000-2003

These studies included computer science, logic, discrete mathematics, artificial intelligence, behavioural psychology, neurobiology, and statistics.

#### Bachelor of Arts in Media Production

Evergreen State College 2000-2003

These studies included video production, photography, audio recording, communication, anthropology, and marketing.

**Continuing Education:** I do weekly studies on Lynda.com and other online learning platforms in order to continually improve myself. Recent certifications from these include:

- One-on-One Adobe Photoshop Series
- One-on-One Adobe Illustrator Series
- Sketch for UX Design
- UX Design Techniques: 6 Part Course
- HTML5: Structure, Syntax, and Semantics

# References

Steve Haak: CEO and VP of Strategy at Solid State Pros LLC, 206-407-9689 Stephen Morrissey: Program Manager at Sinclair Digital, 206-475-1290 Daniel Carpenter: CEO and Senior Designer at Motive LLC, 206-795-0189 Kieran O'Mahony: Neuroscientist at UW and NED Learning, 206-499-0176 Paul Clifton: Associate System Administrator at Nintendo, 208-982-7115